<resources>
    <string name="app_name">MyPlanet</string>
    <string name="get_started">GET STARTED</string>
    <string name="click_the_below_button_for_continue">Click the below button for continue</string>
    <string name="are_you_ready_for_exploration">Are you ready for exploration?</string>
    <string name="my_planet_app">My Planet</string>
    <string name="image">image</string>
    <string name="gridview">GridView</string>
    <string name="hello_welcome_back">Hello, Welcome Back</string>
    <string name="listview">ListView</string>
    <string name="gridHorizontal">GridHorizontal</string>
    <string name="gridVertical">gridVertical</string>
    <string name="my_nplanet">My\nPlanet</string>
    <string name="star">star</string>
    <string name="rocket">rocket</string>
    <string name="astronaut">Astronaut</string>

    <integer-array name="Data_Photo_Planet">
        <item>@drawable/mercury</item>
        <item>@drawable/venus</item>
        <item>@drawable/earth</item>
        <item>@drawable/mars</item>
        <item>@drawable/jupiter</item>
        <item>@drawable/saturn</item>
        <item>@drawable/uranus</item>
        <item>@drawable/neptune</item>
    </integer-array>

    <string-array name="Data_Name_Planet">
        <item>Mercury</item>
        <item>Venus</item>
        <item>Earth</item>
        <item>Mars</item>
        <item>Jupiter</item>
        <item>Saturn</item>
        <item>Uranus</item>
        <item>Neptune</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Data_Desc_Planet">
        <item>
            Mercury is the smallest planet in our solar system and is located closest to the sun. It has a diameter of about 4,880 kilometers, which is roughly one-third the size of Earth, and a mass of approximately 5.5% of Earth\'s mass. Due to its proximity to the sun, Mercury has a very short orbital period of just 88 Earth days.\n
            \nMercury is a rocky planet with a heavily cratered surface, similar in appearance to the Earth\'s moon. Its surface is also marked by long, winding ridges and cliffs, called scarps, which are believed to have formed as the planet cooled and contracted over time. The planet has no atmosphere to speak of, and its surface is subject to extreme temperature variations, with temperatures ranging from -290 degrees Fahrenheit (-180 degrees Celsius) at night to 800 degrees Fahrenheit (430 degrees Celsius) during the day.\n
            \nDespite its small size, Mercury has a surprisingly active geology, with evidence of past volcanic activity and ongoing tectonic activity. The planet also has a weak magnetic field, which is thought to be generated by a partially molten core.\n
            \nMercury is a difficult planet to observe from Earth due to its proximity to the sun, and only two spacecraft have ever visited the planet: NASA\'s Mariner 10 in 1974-75 and Messenger in 2011-2015. These missions provided important insights into Mercury\'s geology, surface features, and magnetic field.\n
            \nAdditionally, some interesting facts about Mercury include:\n
            \n1.Despite being the closest planet to the sun, it is not the hottest planet in the solar system. Venus, which has a thick atmosphere that traps heat, has a higher average temperature.\n
            \n2.Mercury is named after the Roman messenger god, who was known for his speed and agility. The planet\'s quick orbit around the sun made it a fitting namesake.\n
            \n3.Mercury is not known to have any moons or rings.\n
            \n4.The planet has been known since ancient times and was observed by many cultures, including the Babylonians, Greeks, and Mayans. However, because of its proximity to the sun, it was often difficult to observe and remained poorly understood until modern times.\n
            \n5.Mercury\'s proximity to the sun makes it a challenging target for spacecraft, as they must withstand intense heat and radiation. The planet\'s gravity well also makes it difficult to enter and exit orbit around the planet. As a result, there have been relatively few missions to Mercury, and much of what we know about the planet comes from remote observations and data analysis.\n
            \n6.There are plans for future missions to Mercury, including the European Space Agency\'s BepiColombo mission, which launched in 2018 and is expected to arrive at the planet in 2025.\n
        </item>

        <item>
            Venus is the second planet from the sun and is the closest planet in size to Earth. It has a diameter of approximately 12,104 kilometers and a mass of about 81.5% that of Earth. Venus is known for its extreme heat and thick, toxic atmosphere.\n
            \nVenus has a thick atmosphere composed mainly of carbon dioxide, with traces of nitrogen and other gases. The atmosphere is so dense that it exerts a surface pressure more than 90 times greater than that of Earth\'s atmosphere. This pressure, combined with the planet\'s close proximity to the sun, creates a runaway greenhouse effect that heats up the planet\'s surface to an average temperature of around 460 degrees Celsius (860 degrees Fahrenheit), making it the hottest planet in our solar system.\n
            \nVenus has a relatively slow rotation, with one day on Venus being longer than one year on the planet. The planet\'s thick atmosphere causes intense winds to circulate around the planet at high speeds, which can reach up to 400 kilometers per hour (250 miles per hour) at the equator.\n
            \nVenus is covered in volcanic plains, mountains, and vast basins. The planet has more than 1,000 volcanoes, including the largest volcano in the solar system, called Maat Mons. Venus also has a variety of surface features, including impact craters, canyons, and valleys.\n
            \nDue to its thick atmosphere, Venus is difficult to study from Earth. However, several missions have been sent to the planet, including NASA\'s Magellan spacecraft, which orbited Venus and mapped its surface in detail from 1990 to 1994. Other missions, such as ESA\'s Venus Express, have studied the planet\'s atmosphere and climate.\n
            \nSome interesting facts about Venus include:\n
            \n1.Venus is often referred to as Earth\'s \"sister planet\" due to its similar size, mass, and composition. However, the two planets have very different environments and surface conditions.\n
            \n2.Venus rotates in the opposite direction to most other planets in the solar system, with the sun rising in the west and setting in the east.\n
            \n3.Venus has phases, like the moon, as seen from Earth.\n
            \n4.Venus is named after the Roman goddess of love and beauty.\n
            \n5.Because of its proximity and similarity to Earth, Venus has been a popular subject of science fiction and popular culture.\n

        </item>

        <item>
            Earth is the third planet from the sun and is the only planet in our solar system known to support life. It has a diameter of approximately 12,742 kilometers and a mass of about 5.97 x 10^24 kilograms.\n
            \nEarth is composed of several layers, including a solid inner core, a liquid outer core, a mantle, and a crust. The planet\'s atmosphere is also divided into several layers, including the troposphere, stratosphere, mesosphere, thermosphere, and exosphere. The atmosphere is mainly composed of nitrogen (78%) and oxygen (21%), with small amounts of other gases such as carbon dioxide, methane, and neon.\n
            \nEarth is known for its diverse and dynamic environment, with a wide range of ecosystems, climates, and geological features. The planet\'s surface is approximately 70% water, with the remaining 30% consisting of landmasses, including continents and islands. Earth\'s climate is driven by the interaction between the atmosphere, oceans, and land, with factors such as solar radiation, atmospheric gases, and ocean currents influencing global temperature and weather patterns.\n
            \nEarth is home to a wide variety of life, from single-celled organisms to complex multicellular organisms. The planet\'s biosphere is interconnected, with organisms interacting with each other and their environment in complex ways. Humans are one of the most dominant species on the planet and have had a significant impact on the environment and other species.\n
            \nSome interesting facts about Earth include:\n
            \n1.Earth is the only known planet with liquid water on its surface, which is essential for the survival of most known life forms.\n
            \n2.Earth\'s magnetic field, which is generated by the planet\'s core, protects the planet from harmful solar radiation and helps to maintain the atmosphere.\n
            \n3.Earth has a relatively large moon, which has played an important role in stabilizing the planet\'s rotation and tides.\n
            \n4.Earth experiences four seasons, which are caused by the tilt of the planet\'s axis relative to its orbit around the sun.\n
            \n5.Earth\'s rotation is gradually slowing down due to tidal forces, which will eventually cause the planet to have longer days.\n
            \n6.Earth is estimated to be around 4.5 billion years old and has undergone significant changes over its history, including the formation of continents, the evolution of life, and the impact of asteroid and comet impacts.\n
        </item>

        <item>
            Mars is the fourth planet from the sun and is also known as the "Red Planet" due to its reddish appearance in the night sky. It has a diameter of approximately 6,779 kilometers and a mass of about 11% that of Earth.\n
            \nMars has a thin atmosphere composed mainly of carbon dioxide, with small amounts of nitrogen and argon. The atmosphere is not thick enough to support life as we know it, and its surface is exposed to harsh radiation from the sun due to the lack of a protective magnetic field.\n
            \nMars is known for its surface features, which include vast deserts, canyons, volcanoes, and impact craters. The planet has the largest volcano in the solar system, called Olympus Mons, which is over three times taller than Mount Everest on Earth. Mars also has the longest canyon in the solar system, called Valles Marineris, which is over 4,000 kilometers long and up to 7 kilometers deep.\n
            \nMars has two small moons, Phobos and Deimos, which are thought to be captured asteroids. The moons are irregularly shaped and have heavily cratered surfaces.\n
            \nMars has been the subject of several missions by space agencies around the world, including NASA\'s Mars rovers and orbiters, which have studied the planet\'s geology, climate, and potential for life. The planet is also a popular target for future human exploration and colonization.\n
            \nSome interesting facts about Mars include:\n
            \n1.Mars has a day and night cycle similar to Earth, with a day lasting approximately 24.6 hours.\n
            \n2.Mars experiences seasons, which are caused by the planet\'s tilt and its elliptical orbit around the sun.\n
            \n3.Mars has polar ice caps, which are composed of frozen carbon dioxide and water.\n
            \n4.Mars is home to the largest canyon in the solar system, called Valles Marineris.\n
            \n5.Mars is named after the Roman god of war due to its reddish appearance, which was associated with blood by the ancient Romans.\n
            \n6.Mars has the potential for future terraforming, which would involve changing the planet\'s environment to make it more habitable for humans.\n
        </item>

        <item>
            Jupiter is the fifth planet from the sun and is the largest planet in our solar system. It has a diameter of approximately 142,984 kilometers, which is more than 11 times the diameter of Earth, and a mass of about 318 times that of Earth.\n
            \nJupiter is composed mainly of hydrogen and helium gas, and does not have a solid surface like the terrestrial planets. Instead, its outer layers are composed of a dense mixture of gas and liquid, which gradually transitions into a metallic hydrogen layer deep in the planet\'s interior.\n
            \nJupiter has a thick atmosphere composed of colorful bands of clouds that rotate around the planet\'s axis. These bands are caused by the planet\'s fast rotation, which completes one rotation in less than 10 hours. Jupiter\'s atmosphere is also home to the Great Red Spot, a giant storm that has been raging for centuries and is larger than the size of Earth.\n
            \nJupiter has a strong magnetic field, which is the strongest of all the planets in our solar system. The magnetic field traps charged particles from the sun, creating intense radiation belts around the planet.\n
            \nJupiter has at least 79 known moons, the four largest of which are called the Galilean moons: Io, Europa, Ganymede, and Callisto. These moons are some of the largest in our solar system and are thought to have subsurface oceans that could potentially harbor life.\n
            \nJupiter is a popular target for exploration by space agencies around the world. Several missions have been sent to Jupiter, including the Galileo spacecraft, which orbited the planet from 1995 to 2003, and the Juno spacecraft, which has been in orbit around Jupiter since 2016 and is studying the planet\'s magnetic field, atmosphere, and interior structure.\n
            \nSome interesting facts about Jupiter include:\n
            \n1.Jupiter has the shortest day of any planet in our solar system, with one rotation taking less than 10 hours.\n
            \n2.Jupiter\'s magnetic field is so strong that it can affect the behavior of other planets in our solar system.\n
            \n3.Jupiter\'s Great Red Spot is a giant storm that has been raging for at least 350 years and is larger than the size of Earth.\n
            \n4.Jupiter has a ring system, although it is much less visible than Saturn\'s rings.\n
            \n5.Jupiter is the largest planet in our solar system and has more than twice the mass of all the other planets in our solar system combined.\n
        </item>

        <item>
            Saturn is the sixth planet from the sun and is the second largest planet in our solar system after Jupiter. It has a diameter of approximately 116,460 kilometers and a mass of about 95 times that of Earth.\n
            \nSaturn is composed mainly of hydrogen and helium gas, with a small rocky core at its center. It has a thick atmosphere composed of colorful bands of clouds that rotate around the planet\'s axis. These bands are similar to those seen on Jupiter, but are less pronounced.\n
            \nSaturn is well-known for its impressive ring system, which consists of thousands of individual rings composed mainly of ice particles and dust. The rings extend outward from the planet\'s equator for a distance of up to 175,000 kilometers.\n
            \nSaturn has at least 82 known moons, the largest of which is called Titan. Titan is the only moon in our solar system known to have a thick atmosphere, and it has a complex chemistry that includes hydrocarbons and nitrogen.\n
            \nSaturn also has several other interesting moons, including Enceladus, which has geysers that spew water vapor and ice particles into space, and Mimas, which has a large impact crater that makes it resemble the "Death Star" from the Star Wars movies.\n
            \nSaturn has a weak magnetic field, which is about 1/20th the strength of Jupiter\'s magnetic field. However, Saturn\'s magnetosphere is still strong enough to trap charged particles from the sun and create auroras at the planet\'s poles.\n
            \nSaturn has been the subject of several missions by space agencies around the world, including NASA\'s Cassini spacecraft, which orbited the planet from 2004 to 2017 and made numerous discoveries about the planet and its moons.\n
            \nSome interesting facts about Saturn include:\n
            \n1.Saturn\'s ring system is the most extensive and complex ring system of any planet in our solar system.\n
            \n2.Saturn has the second largest moon in our solar system, called Titan, which has a thick atmosphere and a complex chemistry.\n
            \n3.Saturn\'s weak magnetic field is still strong enough to create auroras at the planet\'s poles.\n
            \n4.Saturn\'s largest moon, Titan, is larger than the planet Mercury.\n
            \n5.Saturn is named after the Roman god of agriculture and wealth.\n
        </item>

        <item>
            Uranus is the seventh planet from the sun and is the third largest planet in our solar system. It has a diameter of approximately 50,724 kilometers and a mass of about 14.5 times that of Earth.\n
            \nUranus is composed mainly of hydrogen, helium, and methane gas, with a small rocky core at its center. It has a thick atmosphere composed of hydrogen and helium, along with trace amounts of methane that give the planet its blue-green color.\
            \nUranus is unique among the planets in our solar system in that it rotates on its side, with its axis tilted at an angle of about 98 degrees relative to its orbit. This means that Uranus experiences extreme seasons, with one pole facing the sun for 42 years while the other pole faces away from the sun for the same period.\n
            \nUranus has a weak magnetic field, which is tilted at an angle of about 60 degrees relative to the planet\'s axis of rotation. This unusual orientation causes the magnetic field to wobble as the planet rotates, which can create auroras at the planet\'s poles.\n
            \nUranus has at least 27 known moons, the largest of which is called Titania. It also has a system of 13 faint rings that are composed mainly of ice particles and dust.\n
            \nUranus has been visited by only one spacecraft, NASA\'s Voyager 2 probe, which flew by the planet in 1986 and made numerous discoveries about the planet and its moons.\n
            \nSome interesting facts about Uranus include:\n
            \n1.Uranus is the only planet in our solar system that rotates on its side.\n
            \n2.Uranus has an extreme axial tilt of about 98 degrees, which causes it to experience extreme seasons.\n
            \n3.Uranus has a faint ring system, which was discovered by astronomers in 1977.\n
            \n4.Uranus has a weak magnetic field that is tilted at an angle of about 60 degrees relative to the planet\'s axis of rotation.\n
            \n5.Uranus is named after the Greek god of the sky.\n
        </item>

        <item>
            Neptune is the eighth and farthest known planet from the sun in our solar system. It has a diameter of approximately 49,244 kilometers and a mass of about 17 times that of Earth.\n
            \nNeptune is composed mainly of hydrogen, helium, and methane gas, with a small rocky core at its center. It has a thick atmosphere composed mainly of hydrogen and helium, along with trace amounts of methane that give the planet its blue color.\n
            \nNeptune has a very dynamic atmosphere, with high-speed winds that can reach up to 2,100 kilometers per hour, making them the fastest in the solar system. The planet also has a series of dark spots and bright clouds, similar to Jupiter\'s Great Red Spot.\n
            \nNeptune has 14 known moons, the largest of which is called Triton. Triton is an icy moon that is thought to have been captured by Neptune\'s gravity and has a highly unusual orbit that is tilted relative to the planet\'s equator.\n
            \nNeptune also has a system of faint rings that are composed mainly of dust particles. The rings were discovered by the Voyager 2 spacecraft, which flew by the planet in 1989.\n
            \nNeptune has a strong magnetic field, which is tilted at an angle of about 47 degrees relative to the planet\'s axis of rotation. This magnetic field traps charged particles from the solar wind and creates auroras at the planet\'s poles.\n
            \nNeptune has been visited by only one spacecraft, NASA\'s Voyager 2 probe, which flew by the planet in 1989 and made numerous discoveries about the planet and its moons.\n
            \nSome interesting facts about Neptune include:\n
            \n1.Neptune is the farthest planet from the sun in our solar system.\n
            \n2.Neptune has a very dynamic atmosphere, with high-speed winds that are the fastest in the solar system.\n
            \n3.Neptune has a system of dark spots and bright clouds, similar to Jupiter\'s Great Red Spot.\n
            \n4.Neptune has a strong magnetic field that is tilted relative to the planet\'s axis of rotation.\n
            \n5.Neptune is named after the Roman god of the sea.\n
        </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Data_Name_Astronaut">
        <item>Frank Borman
            \n-Apollo 8 (1968)</item>
        <item>James Lovell
            \n-apollo 8 (1968)
            \n-Apollo 13 (1970)</item>
        <item>William Anders
            \n-Apollo 8 (1968)</item>
        <item>Neil Armstrong
            \n-Apollo 11 (1969)</item>
        <item>Edwin "Buzz" Aldrin
            \n-Apollo 11 (1969)</item>
        <item>Michael Collins
            \n-Apollo 11 (1969)</item>
        <item>Alan Shepard
            \n-Apollo 14 (1971)</item>
        <item>Edgar Mitchell
            \n-Apollo 14 (1971)</item>
        <item>Stuart Roosa
            \n-Apollo 14 (1971)</item>
        <item>David Scott
            \n-Apollo 15 (1971)</item>
        <item>James Irwin
            \n-Apollo 15 (1971)</item>
        <item>Alfred Worden
            \n-Apollo 15 (1971)</item>
        <item>John Young
            \n-Apollo 16 (1972)</item>
        <item>Charles Duke
            \n-Apollo 16 (1972)</item>
        <item>Eugene Cernan
            \n-Apollo 17 (1972)</item>
        <item>Harrison Schmitt
            \n-Apollo 17 (1972)</item>
        <item>Thomas Stafford
            \n-Apollo Soyuz Test Project (1975)</item>
        <item>Vance Brand
            \n-Apollo Soyuz Test Project (1975)</item>
        <item>Deke Slayton
            \n-Apollo Soyuz Test Project (1975)</item>
        <item>Paul Weitz
            \n-Skylab 2 (1973)</item>
        <item>Alan Bean
            \n-Skylab 3 (1973)</item>
        <item>Owen Garriott
            \n-Skylab 3 (1973)</item>
        <item>Jack Lousma
            \n-Skylab 3 (1973)
            \n-STS-3 (1982)</item>
    </string-array>

    <integer-array name="Data_Photo_Astronaut">
        <item>@drawable/frankborman</item>
        <item>@drawable/jameslovell</item>
        <item>@drawable/williamanders</item>
        <item>@drawable/neilarmstrong</item>
        <item>@drawable/edwinaldrin</item>
        <item>@drawable/michaelcollins</item>
        <item>@drawable/alanshepard</item>
        <item>@drawable/edgarmitchell</item>
        <item>@drawable/stuartroosa</item>
        <item>@drawable/davidscott</item>
        <item>@drawable/jamesirwin</item>
        <item>@drawable/alfredworden</item>
        <item>@drawable/johnyoung</item>
        <item>@drawable/charlesduke</item>
        <item>@drawable/eugenecernan</item>
        <item>@drawable/harrisonschmitt</item>
        <item>@drawable/thomasstafford</item>
        <item>@drawable/vancebrand</item>
        <item>@drawable/dekeslayton</item>
        <item>@drawable/paulweitz</item>
        <item>@drawable/alanbean</item>
        <item>@drawable/owengarriott</item>
        <item>@drawable/jacklousma</item>
    </integer-array>

    <string-array name="Data_Desc_Astronaut">
        <item>
            Frank Borman is a retired American astronaut and engineer who gained worldwide recognition as the commander of the historic Apollo 8 mission in 1968. Born in 1928, Borman had a distinguished career in the United States Air Force as a fighter pilot and test pilot before being selected as an astronaut by NASA. As the commander of Apollo 8, Borman and his crewmates became the first humans to orbit the Moon,witnessing the famous Earthrise and paving the way for the Apollo 11 Moon landing. After leaving NASA, Borman pursued a successful career in the business sector and has been recognized with numerous awards for his contributions to space exploration.\n
            \nIn addition to his achievements in space, Borman has been an advocate for environmental causes and has been involved in various philanthropic endeavors. He is widely regarded as a pioneering figure in space exploration and remains an important figure in American space history, known for his leadership and accomplishments in advancing humanity\'s reach beyond Earth.
        </item>
        <item>
            James Lovell is a retired American astronaut and naval aviator who is best known for his role as the commander of the Apollo 13 mission, which became known as a "successful failure" due to the dramatic events that unfolded during the mission. Born on March 25, 1928, in Cleveland, Ohio, Lovell had a distinguished career as an astronaut and military officer.\n
            \nLovell\'s early career was in the United States Navy, where he served as a test pilot and later as an astronaut. He was selected by NASA in 1962 as part of the second group of astronauts known as the "New Nine." Lovell went on to serve as the pilot of Gemini 7 in 1965 and the commander of Gemini 12 in 1966, before commanding the historic Apollo 13 mission in 1970. During Apollo 13, Lovell and his crewmates encountered a life-threatening oxygen tank explosion that crippled their spacecraft, but they successfully returned to Earth after enduring harrowing challenges and making critical decisions.\n
            \nAfter his career as an astronaut, Lovell retired from the Navy and pursued various business ventures. He has been recognized with numerous awards for his contributions to space exploration, and is known for his resilience, leadership, and courage in the face of adversity during the Apollo 13 mission. Lovell\'s story has been celebrated in books, movies, and documentaries, and he remains a revered figure in American space history.\n
        </item>
        <item>
            William Anders is a former American astronaut, engineer, and businessman who is best known for his role as the lunar module pilot on the Apollo 8 mission, the first manned spacecraft to orbit the Moon. Born on October 17, 1933, in Hong Kong, Anders had a notable career as an astronaut and aerospace executive.\n
            \nAnders began his career as an Air Force officer and later joined NASA, where he was selected as an astronaut in 1963 as part of the third group of astronauts known as the "Fourteen." He served as the lunar module pilot for Apollo 8 in 1968, during which he and his crewmates, Frank Borman and James Lovell, became the first humans to travel to the Moon and witness the famous Earthrise. Anders\' iconic photograph of the Earthrise, showing the Earth rising above the lunar horizon, became one of the most iconic images of space exploration.\n
            \nAfter his career as an astronaut, Anders held various executive roles in the aerospace industry and worked in the private sector. He has been recognized with numerous awards for his contributions to space exploration and remains an important figure in American space history. Anders\' legacy as an astronaut and his iconic photograph continue to inspire generations of space enthusiasts and highlight the beauty and fragility of our planet Earth.
        </item>
        <item>
            Neil Armstrong was an American astronaut and engineer who is widely recognized as the first human to set foot on the Moon. Born on August 5, 1930, in Wapakoneta, Ohio, Armstrong had a distinguished career as a pilot, engineer, and astronaut.
            \nArmstrong served as a naval aviator and test pilot before being selected as an astronaut by NASA in 1962 as part of the second group of astronauts known as the "New Nine." He made history on July 20, 1969, as the commander of the Apollo 11 mission, when he became the first person to step onto the lunar surface, uttering the famous words, "That\'s one small step for man, one giant leap for mankind." Armstrong\'s achievement marked a monumental moment in human history, and his name is forever etched in the annals of space exploration.
            \nAfter his historic Moon landing, Armstrong remained involved in aerospace and engineering pursuits, and he was recognized with numerous awards for his contributions to science, engineering, and space exploration. His legacy as a pioneering astronaut and his iconic role in the Apollo 11 mission continue to inspire generations of space enthusiasts and serve as a testament to humanity\'s curiosity, ingenuity, and ability to explore the unknown.
        </item>
        <item>
            Edwin "Buzz" Aldrin is an American astronaut, engineer, and former Air Force pilot who is best known for being the lunar module pilot on the Apollo 11 mission, which was the first manned spacecraft to land on the Moon. Born on January 20, 1930, in Glen Ridge, New Jersey, Aldrin has had a notable career in aerospace and space exploration.
            \nAldrin served as an Air Force pilot during the Korean War, and later earned a doctorate in astronautics from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. He was selected as an astronaut by NASA in 1963 as part of the third group of astronauts known as the "Fourteen." Aldrin made history on July 20, 1969, when he and Neil Armstrong became the first humans to set foot on the lunar surface during the Apollo 11 mission. He spent over 21 hours on the Moon, conducting experiments and collecting samples, and his iconic photograph of Armstrong on the Moon\'s surface has become an enduring image of the Apollo Moon landing.
            \nAfter his career as an astronaut, Aldrin remained active in the aerospace and space communities, advocating for continued human exploration of space and promoting space education. He has received numerous awards for his contributions to space exploration, and his role as a pioneering astronaut and his accomplishments during the Apollo 11 mission continue to inspire future generations of astronauts and space enthusiasts alike.
        </item>
        <item>
            Michael Collins was an American astronaut, test pilot, and engineer who is best known for his role as the command module pilot on the Apollo 11 mission, the historic mission that resulted in the first manned landing on the Moon. Born on October 31, 1930, in Rome, Italy, Collins had a distinguished career as an astronaut and aviation professional.
            \nCollins served as a fighter pilot in the U.S. Air Force and later joined NASA as an astronaut in 1963 as part of the third group of astronauts known as the "Fourteen." He served as the command module pilot for Apollo 11 in 1969, during which he orbited the Moon while his fellow crewmates, Neil Armstrong and Edwin "Buzz" Aldrin, descended to the lunar surface. Collins played a crucial role in the success of the mission, piloting the command module, which acted as the "mothership" for the lunar module and provided support to the astronauts on the lunar surface.
            \nAfter his career as an astronaut, Collins served in various leadership roles in the aerospace industry and pursued other interests. He received numerous awards for his contributions to space exploration, and his role as the command module pilot on Apollo 11 is remembered as a vital part of the historic Moon landing. Collins\' legacy as an astronaut and his significant contributions to human space exploration continue to inspire future generations of astronauts and space enthusiasts.
        </item>
        <item>
            Alan Shepard was an American astronaut, naval aviator, and businessman who was one of the original seven Mercury astronauts and the first American to travel to space. Born on November 18, 1923, in East Derry, New Hampshire, Shepard had a distinguished career as an astronaut and aviation professional.
            \nShepard served as a Navy test pilot and was selected as one of the Mercury astronauts by NASA in 1959. He made history on May 5, 1961, when he became the first American to travel to space aboard the Mercury spacecraft Freedom 7, making a suborbital flight lasting 15 minutes and 28 seconds. Shepard\'s successful mission marked a significant milestone in the early days of human space exploration and paved the way for future manned space missions.
            \nAfter his pioneering flight, Shepard went on to command the Apollo 14 mission in 1971, during which he became the fifth person to walk on the Moon. He spent a total of 9 hours and 17 minutes on the lunar surface, conducting experiments and collecting samples. Shepard\'s achievements as an astronaut, his contributions to science, and his pioneering spirit continue to inspire generations of astronauts and space enthusiasts, leaving an indelible mark on the history of space exploration.
        </item>
        <item>
            Edgar Mitchell was an American astronaut, naval officer, and aviator who was the Lunar Module Pilot on the Apollo 14 mission, making him the sixth person to walk on the Moon. Born on September 17, 1930, in Hereford, Texas, Mitchell had a notable career as an astronaut and space explorer.
            \nMitchell served as a Navy pilot and was selected as an astronaut by NASA in 1966 as part of the fifth group of astronauts known as the "Original 19." He flew on the Apollo 14 mission in 1971, during which he and his fellow crewmates, Alan Shepard and Stuart Roosa, successfully landed on the Moon. Mitchell spent a total of 9 hours and 17 minutes on the lunar surface, conducting experiments, collecting samples, and exploring the Moon\'s surface.
            \nAfter his career as an astronaut, Mitchell pursued interests in consciousness, spirituality, and environmental advocacy. He founded the Institute of Noetic Sciences, a research organization focused on exploring the intersection of science and spirituality. Mitchell\'s legacy as an astronaut, his contributions to scientific research, and his exploration of the Moon continue to inspire future generations of astronauts and space enthusiasts.
        </item>
        <item>
            Stuart Roosa was an American astronaut, pilot, and former smokejumper who served as the Command Module Pilot on the Apollo 14 mission, the eighth manned mission in NASA\'s Apollo program. Born on August 16, 1933, in Durango, Colorado, Roosa had a notable career as an astronaut and aviation professional.
            \nRoosa served as an Air Force pilot and was selected as an astronaut by NASA in 1966 as part of the fifth group of astronauts known as the "Original 19." He flew on the Apollo 14 mission in 1971, during which he orbited the Moon while his fellow crewmates, Alan Shepard and Edgar Mitchell, descended to the lunar surface. Roosa played a crucial role in the success of the mission, piloting the command module, which provided support to the astronauts on the lunar surface and conducted scientific experiments from lunar orbit.
            \nAfter his career as an astronaut, Roosa pursued interests in forestry and conservation. He served as a spokesman for tree planting and conservation efforts, and a variety of tree seeds were taken with him on the Apollo 14 mission and later planted as part of the "Moon Trees" program. Roosa\'s contributions to space exploration, his dedication to conservation efforts, and his role as a command module pilot on Apollo 14 are remembered as significant achievements in the history of human spaceflight.
        </item>
        <item>
            David Scott is an American astronaut, engineer, and former Air Force pilot who is best known for his involvement in NASA\'s Apollo program. Born on June 6, 1932, in San Antonio, Texas, Scott had a distinguished career as an astronaut and aviation professional.
            \nScott served as an Air Force pilot and was selected as an astronaut by NASA in 1963 as part of the third group of astronauts known as the "Fourteen." He flew on three NASA missions, including Gemini 8, Apollo 9, and Apollo 15. Scott\'s most notable mission was Apollo 15, during which he became the seventh person to walk on the Moon and the first to drive the Lunar Roving Vehicle (LRV), a lunar exploration vehicle used to traverse the lunar surface.
            \nAs Commander of Apollo 15, Scott conducted a series of scientific experiments on the lunar surface, including the deployment of the first lunar rover, which greatly expanded the range of exploration on the Moon. He also conducted the famous "hammer and feather" experiment, demonstrating Galileo\'s theory that objects of different masses fall at the same rate in a vacuum. Scott\'s contributions to scientific research and his pioneering spirit as an astronaut continue to inspire future generations of space explorers.
        </item>
        <item>
            James Irwin was an American astronaut, engineer, and former Air Force pilot who is best known for his role as the Lunar Module Pilot on the Apollo 15 mission, making him the eighth person to walk on the Moon. Born on March 17, 1930, in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, Irwin had a notable career as an astronaut and aviation professional.
            \nIrwin served as an Air Force pilot and was selected as an astronaut by NASA in 1966 as part of the fifth group of astronauts known as the "Original 19." He flew on the Apollo 15 mission in 1971, during which he spent a total of 3 days on the lunar surface, conducting scientific experiments, collecting samples, and exploring the Moon\'s surface.
            \nAs Lunar Module Pilot of Apollo 15, Irwin made significant contributions to the scientific research conducted during the mission, including the discovery of the "Genesis Rock," a rock believed to be over 4 billion years old and one of the oldest rocks ever found on the Moon. Irwin also became known for his deep spiritual experiences during the mission, which led him to become an advocate for the integration of faith and science. His role as an astronaut and his contributions to lunar exploration continue to be remembered as significant milestones in human spaceflight history.
        </item>
        <item>
            Alfred Worden was an American astronaut, engineer, and former Air Force pilot who served as the Command Module Pilot on the Apollo 15 mission, the fourth manned mission to land on the Moon. Born on February 7, 1932, in Jackson, Michigan, Worden had a distinguished career as an astronaut and aviation professional.
            \nWorden served as an Air Force pilot and was selected as an astronaut by NASA in 1966 as part of the fifth group of astronauts known as the "Original 19." He flew on the Apollo 15 mission in 1971, during which he orbited the Moon alone in the command module "Endeavour" while his fellow crewmates, David Scott and James Irwin, conducted scientific experiments and explored the lunar surface.
            \nAs Command Module Pilot, Worden played a crucial role in the success of the Apollo 15 mission, providing support to the lunar surface crew and conducting scientific observations from lunar orbit. He also conducted a series of spacewalks, becoming the first astronaut to perform "deep space" EVA (extravehicular activity) outside the Earth\'s atmosphere. Worden\'s contributions to lunar orbit operations and his pioneering achievements during the Apollo 15 mission are remembered as significant milestones in the history of human space exploration.
        </item>
        <item>
            John Young was an American astronaut, naval officer, and aviator who served as a commander, pilot, and astronaut on multiple NASA missions. Born on September 24, 1930, in San Francisco, California, Young had a remarkable career as an astronaut and aviation professional.
            \nYoung was selected as an astronaut by NASA in 1962 as part of the second group of astronauts known as the "New Nine." He flew on a total of six space missions, including Gemini 3, Gemini 10, Apollo 10, Apollo 16, STS-1 (Space Shuttle Columbia), and STS-9 (Space Shuttle Columbia). He is the only astronaut to have flown on Gemini, Apollo, and Space Shuttle missions, and he was also the first astronaut to command four different types of spacecraft.
            \nYoung\'s contributions to space exploration were numerous and significant. He served as the Command Module Pilot on Apollo 10, which was a crucial mission that paved the way for the first manned Moon landing. He also walked on the Moon as the Commander of Apollo 16, conducting scientific experiments and exploring the lunar surface. In addition, Young had a long and illustrious career with NASA, serving in various leadership roles, including Chief of the Astronaut Office and Associate Administrator for the Office of Space Shuttle Programs. His achievements as an astronaut and his dedication to space exploration continue to inspire future generations of space adventurers.
        </item>
        <item>
            Charles Duke, also known as Charlie Duke, is an American astronaut, former Air Force officer, and lunar module pilot who is best known for his role as the tenth person to walk on the Moon during the Apollo 16 mission. Born on October 3, 1935, in Charlotte, North Carolina, Duke had a distinguished career as an astronaut and aviation professional.
            \nDuke was selected as an astronaut by NASA in 1966 as part of the fifth group of astronauts known as the "Original 19." He flew on the Apollo 16 mission in 1972, during which he spent a total of 3 days on the lunar surface, conducting scientific experiments, collecting samples, and exploring the Moon\'s surface alongside his fellow astronaut, John Young.
            \nAs Lunar Module Pilot of Apollo 16, Duke made significant contributions to the scientific research conducted during the mission, including the deployment of the Lunar Roving Vehicle (LRV), which allowed for extended exploration of the lunar surface. He also conducted three moonwalks, during which he and Young traveled over 16 miles in the LRV, making them the "driving astronauts" of the Apollo missions. Duke\'s role as an astronaut and his contributions to lunar exploration are remembered as significant milestones in human spaceflight history.
        </item>
        <item>
            Eugene Cernan was an American astronaut, naval aviator, and engineer who served as the Commander of the Apollo 17 mission, making him the last person to walk on the Moon as of the current date. Born on March 14, 1934, in Chicago, Illinois, Cernan had a distinguished career as an astronaut and aviation professional.
            \nCernan was selected as an astronaut by NASA in 1963 as part of the third group of astronauts known as the "Fourteen." He flew on three space missions: Gemini 9A, Apollo 10, and Apollo 17. As the Commander of Apollo 17, Cernan and his fellow astronaut, Harrison Schmitt, spent over 3 days on the lunar surface, conducting scientific experiments, collecting samples, and exploring the Moon\'s surface using the Lunar Roving Vehicle (LRV).
            \nCernan\'s legacy as an astronaut includes being the last human to set foot on the Moon, as well as his pioneering achievements in space exploration. He made significant contributions to lunar research and exploration during his career, and his passion for space and his commitment to advancing human spaceflight continue to inspire future generations of astronauts and space enthusiasts.
        </item>
        <item>
            Harrison "Jack" Schmitt is an American geologist, astronaut, and former U.S. Senator who is best known for his role as the lunar module pilot of Apollo 17, the last manned mission to the Moon as of the current date. Born on July 3, 1935, in Santa Rita, New Mexico, Schmitt had a remarkable career as an astronaut and geologist.
            \nSchmitt was selected as an astronaut by NASA in 1965 as part of the fifth group of astronauts known as the "Original 19." He flew on the Apollo 17 mission in 1972, during which he spent a total of 3 days on the lunar surface, conducting scientific experiments, collecting samples, and exploring the Moon\'s surface alongside his fellow astronaut, Eugene Cernan.
            \nAs the first and only scientist-astronaut to visit the Moon, Schmitt made significant contributions to the scientific research conducted during the Apollo 17 mission. He conducted three moonwalks, during which he and Cernan traveled over 22 miles in the Lunar Roving Vehicle (LRV), collecting valuable data and samples that continue to advance our understanding of the Moon\'s geology and history. Schmitt\'s role as an astronaut and his contributions to lunar exploration are remembered as significant achievements in human spaceflight history, and his work as a geologist has also had a lasting impact on our understanding of planetary geology.
        </item>
        <item>
            Thomas P. Stafford is an American astronaut, retired Air Force general, and former NASA astronaut who played a significant role in the early years of human spaceflight. Born on July 17, 1930, in Weatherford, Oklahoma, Stafford had a distinguished career as an astronaut, aviator, and aerospace engineer.
            \nStafford was selected as an astronaut by NASA in 1962 as part of the second group of astronauts known as the "New Nine." He flew on four space missions, including Gemini 6A, Gemini 9A, Apollo 10, and Apollo-Soyuz Test Project (ASTP). He served as commander for both Apollo 10 and ASTP missions.
            \nAs commander of Apollo 10, Stafford played a pivotal role in the final dress rehearsal for the Apollo 11 lunar landing, testing the lunar module in lunar orbit and making critical decisions that contributed to the success of the Apollo 11 mission. He also played a key role in the Apollo-Soyuz Test Project, a joint mission with the Soviet Union that marked the first international human spaceflight collaboration.
            \nThroughout his career, Stafford\'s leadership, expertise, and contributions to human spaceflight have been widely recognized and celebrated. He has received numerous awards and honors for his achievements in aviation and space exploration, and his legacy as an astronaut and aerospace pioneer continues to inspire future generations of astronauts and space enthusiasts.
        </item>
        <item>
            Vance Brand is an American astronaut, former naval aviator, and aerospace engineer who has had a distinguished career in space exploration. Born on May 9, 1931, in Longmont, Colorado, Brand has flown on four space missions and has made significant contributions to human spaceflight.
            \nBrand was selected as an astronaut by NASA in 1966 as part of the fifth group of astronauts known as the "Original 19." He flew on the Apollo-Soyuz Test Project (ASTP), Skylab 3, and Space Shuttle missions STS-5 and STS-41-B. He served as commander for the STS-5 and STS-41-B missions.
            \nAs commander of STS-5, which was the first operational flight of the Space Shuttle program, Brand played a pivotal role in demonstrating the capabilities of the Space Shuttle orbiter as a reusable spacecraft. He also served as commander for STS-41-B, which was the eleventh flight of the Space Shuttle program and included the deployment of two communication satellites.
            \nThroughout his career, Brand\'s contributions to space exploration and his leadership as an astronaut have been widely recognized and celebrated. He has received numerous awards and honors for his achievements in aviation and spaceflight, and his dedication to advancing human space exploration continues to inspire future generations of astronauts and space enthusiasts.
        </item>
        <item>
            Deke Slayton, whose full name is Donald Kent Slayton, was an American astronaut and commercial pilot who played a significant role in the early years of human spaceflight. Born on March 1, 1924, in Sparta, Wisconsin, Slayton had a remarkable career as an astronaut and aerospace engineer.
            \nSlayton was selected as one of the original Mercury Seven astronauts by NASA in 1959. He was slated to fly on the Mercury-Atlas 7 mission, but due to a medical condition, he was grounded and had to wait until 1972 to make his first and only spaceflight as part of the Apollo-Soyuz Test Project (ASTP). Slayton served as the docking module pilot for ASTP, which was a joint mission between the United States and the Soviet Union and marked the first international human spaceflight collaboration.
            \nAfter his time as an astronaut, Slayton played a key role in managing NASA\'s astronaut office and was instrumental in the selection of astronauts for subsequent missions, including the Space Shuttle program. He also served as a consultant and advocate for commercial space endeavors, contributing to the development of the private space industry.
            \nSlayton\'s contributions to human spaceflight and his leadership as an astronaut have been widely recognized and celebrated. He received numerous awards and honors for his achievements in aviation and space exploration, and his legacy as an astronaut and advocate for commercial space continues to inspire future generations of astronauts and space enthusiasts.
        </item>
        <item>
            Paul Weitz, whose full name is Paul Joseph Weitz, was an American astronaut, naval aviator, and aerospace engineer who made significant contributions to human spaceflight. Born on July 25, 1932, in Erie, Pennsylvania, Weitz had a distinguished career as an astronaut and engineer.
            \nWeitz was selected as an astronaut by NASA in 1966 as part of the fifth group of astronauts known as the "Original 19." He flew on two space missions, Skylab 2 and STS-6. He served as commander for the STS-6 mission, which was the maiden flight of the Space Shuttle Challenger.
            \nAs commander of STS-6, Weitz played a pivotal role in leading the successful mission, which included the deployment of a communications satellite and conducting scientific experiments. He was also known for his contributions to the development of the Space Shuttle program and the training of future astronauts.
            \nThroughout his career, Weitz\'s expertise in aviation and space exploration was widely recognized and respected. He received numerous awards and honors for his achievements, and his legacy as an astronaut and engineer continues to inspire future generations of astronauts and space enthusiasts.
        </item>
        <item>
            Alan Bean, whose full name is Alan LaVern Bean, was an American astronaut, naval aviator, and artist who made significant contributions to human spaceflight and the arts. Born on March 15, 1932, in Wheeler, Texas, Bean had a distinguished career as an astronaut and artist.
            \nBean was selected as an astronaut by NASA in 1963 as part of the third group of astronauts known as the "NASA Astronaut Group 3." He flew on two space missions, Apollo 12 and Skylab 3. As part of Apollo 12, Bean became the fourth person to walk on the moon and spent a total of 7 hours and 45 minutes on the lunar surface. He conducted experiments and collected lunar samples, contributing to our understanding of the moon\'s geology.
            \nAfter retiring from NASA, Bean pursued his passion for art and became known for his paintings depicting his experiences as an astronaut on the moon. His artwork captured the beauty and majesty of space exploration and was widely recognized and celebrated.
            \nThroughout his career, Bean\'s contributions to human spaceflight and the arts were highly esteemed. He received numerous awards and honors for his achievements, and his legacy as an astronaut and artist continues to inspire future generations of astronauts, artists, and space enthusiasts.
        </item>
        <item>
            Owen Kay Garriott, known as Owen Garriott, was an American astronaut, scientist, and engineer who made significant contributions to human spaceflight and scientific research. Born on November 22, 1930, in Enid, Oklahoma, Garriott had a distinguished career as an astronaut and scientist.
            \nGarriott was selected as an astronaut by NASA in 1965 as part of the fourth group of astronauts known as the "NASA Astronaut Group 4." He flew on two space missions, Skylab 3 and STS-9. As part of Skylab 3, Garriott spent a total of 60 days in space, conducting experiments and research related to solar astronomy, Earth observation, and human physiology.
            \nGarriott was known for his expertise in scientific research and conducted numerous experiments during his space missions, contributing to our understanding of space, Earth, and the human body. He also served as a payload specialist on STS-9, where he conducted additional experiments in collaboration with international partners.
            \nAfter retiring from NASA, Garriott continued his career as a scientist and made significant contributions to research in the fields of Earth observation, remote sensing, and environmental studies. His work as an astronaut and scientist was widely recognized and honored with numerous awards and accolades.
            \nGarriott\'s legacy as an astronaut, scientist, and engineer continues to inspire future generations of astronauts, scientists, and space enthusiasts, and his contributions to human spaceflight and scientific research remain an enduring part of space exploration history.
        </item>
        <item>
            Jack Robert Lousma, known as Jack Lousma, is an American astronaut, engineer, and former politician who has made significant contributions to human spaceflight, engineering, and public service. Born on February 29, 1936, in Grand Rapids, Michigan, Lousma has had a distinguished career as an astronaut, engineer, and public servant.
            \nLousma was selected as an astronaut by NASA in 1966 as part of the fifth group of astronauts known as the "Original 19." He flew on two space missions, Skylab 3 and STS-3. As part of Skylab 3, Lousma spent a total of 59 days in space, conducting experiments and research related to solar astronomy, Earth observation, and human physiology. He also served as commander for STS-3, which was the third orbital test flight of the Space Shuttle program.
            \nLousma\'s expertise as an engineer and astronaut was widely recognized, and he made significant contributions to the development of the Space Shuttle program and the advancement of space exploration technology. After retiring from NASA, Lousma continued his career as an engineer and later served as a Republican member of the Michigan State Senate.
            \nLousma\'s legacy as an astronaut, engineer, and public servant continues to inspire future generations of astronauts, engineers, and public servants, and his contributions to human spaceflight, engineering, and public service remain a notable part of space exploration and public service history.
        </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Data_Name_Apollo">
        <item>Apollo 1 (AS-204)</item>
        <item>Apollo 7 (AS-205)</item>
        <item>Apollo 8 (AS-503)</item>
        <item>Apollo 9 (AS-504)</item>
        <item>Apollo 10 (AS-505)</item>
        <item>Apollo 11 (AS-506)</item>
        <item>Apollo 12 (AS-507)</item>
        <item>Apollo 13 (AS-508)</item>
        <item>Apollo 14 (AS-509)</item>
        <item>Apollo 15 (AS-510)</item>
        <item>Apollo 16 (AS-511)</item>
        <item>Apollo 17 (AS-512)</item>
    </string-array>

    <integer-array name="Data_Photo_Apollo">
        <item>@drawable/apolloone</item>
        <item>@drawable/apolloseven</item>
        <item>@drawable/apolloeight</item>
        <item>@drawable/apollonine</item>
        <item>@drawable/apolloten</item>
        <item>@drawable/apolloeleven</item>
        <item>@drawable/apollotwelve</item>
        <item>@drawable/apollothirteen</item>
        <item>@drawable/apolloforteen</item>
        <item>@drawable/apollofifteen</item>
        <item>@drawable/apollosixteen</item>
        <item>@drawable/apolloseventeen</item>
    </integer-array>

    <string-array name="Data_Desc_Apollo">
        <item>
            Apollo 1 (AS-204): Originally scheduled for February 21, 1967, was the first manned mission of the Apollo program. However, on January 27, 1967, during a launch pad test, a fire broke out inside the Apollo 1 spacecraft, resulting in the tragic loss of all three crew members - Virgil "Gus" Grissom, Edward H. White II, and Roger B. Chaffee. The accident was a devastating setback for the Apollo program and led to a comprehensive review of spacecraft design, safety protocols, and crew training, resulting in significant improvements to prevent similar accidents in the future.
        </item>

        <item>
            Apollo 7 (AS-205): Apollo 7, launched on October 11, 1968, marked the first manned flight of the Apollo program. The crew of Walter Schirra, Donn Eisele, and Walter Cunningham orbited the Earth for 11 days, conducting tests and evaluations of the spacecraft\'s systems and capabilities. This mission proved that the spacecraft and its systems were ready for future lunar missions, and it paved the way for the upcoming Apollo lunar landings.
        </item>

        <item>
            Apollo 8 (AS-503): Apollo 8, launched on December 21, 1968, was the first manned mission to leave Earth\'s orbit and travel to the Moon. The crew of Frank Borman, James Lovell, and William Anders orbited the Moon 10 times, capturing stunning images of the lunar surface and becoming the first humans to witness and photograph an Earthrise from space. This mission was a significant milestone in human space exploration, setting the stage for the eventual lunar landings.
        </item>

        <item>
            Apollo 9 (AS-504): Apollo 9, launched on March 3, 1969, was a critical mission to test the Lunar Module(LM) in Earth orbit. The crew of James McDivitt, David Scott, and Russell Schweickart conducted a series of maneuvers to test the LM\'s performance and its ability to dock with the Command Module(CM). They also performed the first manned flight of the Lunar Module, making it a crucial step towards the lunar landing.
        </item>

        <item>
            Apollo 10 (AS-505): Apollo 10, launched on May 18, 1969, was a dress rehearsal for the lunar landing. The crew of Thomas Stafford, John Young, and Eugene Cernan orbited the Moon, testing the LM\'s performance in lunar orbit and conducting various tasks that would be required for the upcoming lunar landing. They descended close to the lunar surface, but did not land, serving as a crucial precursor to the historic Apollo 11 mission.
        </item>

        <item>
            Apollo 11 (AS-506), launched on July 16, 1969, was the first manned mission to land on the Moon. The crew of Neil Armstrong, Michael Collins, and Edwin "Buzz" Aldrin made history on July 20, 1969, when Armstrong and Aldrin became the first humans to set foot on the Moon, famously declaring, "That\'s one small step for [a] man, one giant leap for mankind." The mission successfully conducted experiments, collected samples, and returned safely to Earth on July 24, 1969, marking a major milestone in human space exploration and fulfilling President John F. Kennedy\'s goal of landing humans on the Moon before the end of the decade.
        </item>

        <item>
            Apollo 12 (AS-507), launched on November 14, 1969, was the second manned lunar landing mission. The crew of Charles "Pete" Conrad, Richard F. Gordon Jr., and Alan L. Bean faced challenges during their mission, including a lightning strike that temporarily knocked out their spacecraft systems during launch. However, they overcame these obstacles and successfully landed on the Moon on November 14, 1969. They conducted experiments, collected samples, and explored the lunar surface, demonstrating the resilience and resourcefulness of the Apollo astronauts. Apollo 12 also marked the first use of the Lunar Module\'s precision landing system, which allowed the astronauts to land within walking distance of the Surveyor III spacecraft, a robotic lander that had landed on the Moon in 1967. This successful landing further validated the precision landing capabilities of the Apollo spacecraft.
        </item>

        <item>
            Apollo 13 (AS-508) was the seventh manned mission of NASA\'s Apollo program launched on April 11, 1970. It encountered a critical failure when an oxygen tank exploded, forcing the crew to abort their lunar landing mission and focus on returning safely to Earth. Through incredible teamwork and innovation, the crew successfully returned to Earth on April 17, 1970, making it a remarkable story of human resilience and ingenuity in the face of adversity. The mission highlighted the risks and challenges of space exploration, and its success continues to be celebrated as a symbol of human exploration and the indomitable spirit of the human quest for knowledge and discovery in space.
        </item>

        <item>
            Apollo 14 (AS-509), launched on January 31, 1971, was the third manned lunar landing mission. The crew of Alan Shepard, Stuart Roosa, and Edgar Mitchell landed on the Moon on February 5, 1971, and conducted experiments, collected samples, and explored the lunar surface. Shepard, who had previously flown on the Mercury-Redstone 3 mission in 1961, famously hit golf balls on the lunar surface with a makeshift club, showcasing the unique challenges and opportunities of human presence on the Moon. Apollo 14 also marked the first use of the Lunar Module\'s Modularized Equipment Stowage Assembly(MESA), which allowed for easier deployment of equipment and instruments on the lunar surface.
        </item>

        <item>
            Apollo 15 (AS-510), launched on July 26, 1971, was the first "J-mission," which involved an extended stay on the lunar surface and increased capabilities for scientific exploration. The crew of David Scott, Alfred Worden, and James Irwin spent nearly three days on the Moon, conducting experiments, collecting samples, and exploring the lunar terrain with the Lunar Roving Vehicle(LRV). They also performed the first deep space EVA(Extra-Vehicular Activity) during the apollo 15 mission, when Scott and Irwin ventured far from the Lunar Module to collect samples from the rim of Hadley Rille, a lunar canyon, and conducted experiments to study the Moon\'s geology, gravity, and atmosphere. Worden, who remained in orbit aboard the Command Module, conducted experiments and performed observations of the lunar surface from a unique vantage point. The mission also carried the first lunar surface experiments package(ALSEP), which included seismometers, spectrometers, and other instruments to gather data on the Moon\'s geophysical properties. Apollo 15 expanded our understanding of the Moon\'s composition and geology, providing valuable insights into its history and evolution.
        </item>

        <item>
            Apollo 16 (AS-511), launched on April 16, 1972, was the fifth manned lunar landing mission. The crew of John Young, Charles Duke, and Thomas Mattingly spent just over three days on the lunar surface, conducting experiments, collecting samples, and exploring the Descartes Highlands region. Young and Duke, who descended to the lunar surface in the Lunar Module, used the Lunar Roving Vehicle(LRV) to cover a larger area and collect samples from multiple locations. Mattingly remained in orbit aboard the Command Module, conducting experiments and observations. Apollo 16 was notable for its geology-focused mission objectives, as the Descartes Highlands were believed to be representative of the Moon\'s ancient crust. The mission yielded important data on the Moon\'s geology, including evidence of ancient volcanism and impact cratering, and provided further insights into the Moon\'s geological history.
        </item>

        <item>
            Apollo 17 (AS-512), launched on December 7, 1972, was the final manned mission of the Apollo program and the last time humans have visited the Moon to date. The crew of Eugene Cernan, Ronald Evans, and Harrison Schmitt spent just over three days on the lunar surface, conducting experiments, collecting samples, and exploring the Taurus-Littrow valley region. Schmitt, a geologist, was the first and only scientist-astronaut to walk on the Moon, providing valuable insights into the Moon\'s composition and history. Cernan and Schmitt also used the Lunar Roving Vehicle(LRV) to cover a larger area and collect samples from multiple locations. Evans remained in orbit aboard the Command Module, conducting experiments and observations. Apollo 17 was notable for its extensive geological investigations, and the samples and data collected during the mission continue to be analyzed and studied by scientists to this day, furthering our understanding of the Moon\'s geology and evolution.
        </item>

    </string-array>


</resources>