<resources>
    <string name="app_name">MyPlanet</string>
    <string name="get_started">GET STARTED</string>
    <string name="click_the_below_button_for_continue">Click the below button for continue</string>
    <string name="are_you_ready_for_exploration">Are you ready for exploration?</string>
    <string name="my_planet_app">My Planet</string>
    <string name="image">image</string>
    <string name="gridview">GridView</string>
    <string name="hello_welcome_back">Hello, Welcome Back</string>
    <string name="listview">ListView</string>
    <string name="gridHorizontal">GridHorizontal</string>
    <string name="gridVertical">gridVertical</string>

    <integer-array name="Data_Photo_Planet">
        <item>@drawable/mercury</item>
        <item>@drawable/venus</item>
        <item>@drawable/earth</item>
        <item>@drawable/mars</item>
        <item>@drawable/jupiter</item>
        <item>@drawable/saturn</item>
        <item>@drawable/uranus</item>
        <item>@drawable/neptune</item>
    </integer-array>

    <string-array name="Data_Name_Planet">
        <item>Mercury</item>
        <item>Venus</item>
        <item>Earth</item>
        <item>Mars</item>
        <item>Jupiter</item>
        <item>Saturn</item>
        <item>Uranus</item>
        <item>Neptune</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Data_Desc_Planet">
        <item>
            Mercury is the smallest planet in our solar system and is located closest to the sun. It has a diameter of about 4,880 kilometers, which is roughly one-third the size of Earth, and a mass of approximately 5.5% of Earth\'s mass. Due to its proximity to the sun, Mercury has a very short orbital period of just 88 Earth days.\n
            \nMercury is a rocky planet with a heavily cratered surface, similar in appearance to the Earth\'s moon. Its surface is also marked by long, winding ridges and cliffs, called scarps, which are believed to have formed as the planet cooled and contracted over time. The planet has no atmosphere to speak of, and its surface is subject to extreme temperature variations, with temperatures ranging from -290 degrees Fahrenheit (-180 degrees Celsius) at night to 800 degrees Fahrenheit (430 degrees Celsius) during the day.\n
            \nDespite its small size, Mercury has a surprisingly active geology, with evidence of past volcanic activity and ongoing tectonic activity. The planet also has a weak magnetic field, which is thought to be generated by a partially molten core.\n
            \nMercury is a difficult planet to observe from Earth due to its proximity to the sun, and only two spacecraft have ever visited the planet: NASA\'s Mariner 10 in 1974-75 and Messenger in 2011-2015. These missions provided important insights into Mercury\'s geology, surface features, and magnetic field.\n
            \nAdditionally, some interesting facts about Mercury include:\n
            \n1.Despite being the closest planet to the sun, it is not the hottest planet in the solar system. Venus, which has a thick atmosphere that traps heat, has a higher average temperature.\n
            \n2.Mercury is named after the Roman messenger god, who was known for his speed and agility. The planet\'s quick orbit around the sun made it a fitting namesake.\n
            \n3.Mercury is not known to have any moons or rings.\n
            \n4.The planet has been known since ancient times and was observed by many cultures, including the Babylonians, Greeks, and Mayans. However, because of its proximity to the sun, it was often difficult to observe and remained poorly understood until modern times.\n
            \n5.Mercury\'s proximity to the sun makes it a challenging target for spacecraft, as they must withstand intense heat and radiation. The planet\'s gravity well also makes it difficult to enter and exit orbit around the planet. As a result, there have been relatively few missions to Mercury, and much of what we know about the planet comes from remote observations and data analysis.\n
            \n6.There are plans for future missions to Mercury, including the European Space Agency\'s BepiColombo mission, which launched in 2018 and is expected to arrive at the planet in 2025.\n
        </item>

        <item>
            Venus is the second planet from the sun and is the closest planet in size to Earth. It has a diameter of approximately 12,104 kilometers and a mass of about 81.5% that of Earth. Venus is known for its extreme heat and thick, toxic atmosphere.\n
            \nVenus has a thick atmosphere composed mainly of carbon dioxide, with traces of nitrogen and other gases. The atmosphere is so dense that it exerts a surface pressure more than 90 times greater than that of Earth\'s atmosphere. This pressure, combined with the planet\'s close proximity to the sun, creates a runaway greenhouse effect that heats up the planet\'s surface to an average temperature of around 460 degrees Celsius (860 degrees Fahrenheit), making it the hottest planet in our solar system.\n
            \nVenus has a relatively slow rotation, with one day on Venus being longer than one year on the planet. The planet\'s thick atmosphere causes intense winds to circulate around the planet at high speeds, which can reach up to 400 kilometers per hour (250 miles per hour) at the equator.\n
            \nVenus is covered in volcanic plains, mountains, and vast basins. The planet has more than 1,000 volcanoes, including the largest volcano in the solar system, called Maat Mons. Venus also has a variety of surface features, including impact craters, canyons, and valleys.\n
            \nDue to its thick atmosphere, Venus is difficult to study from Earth. However, several missions have been sent to the planet, including NASA\'s Magellan spacecraft, which orbited Venus and mapped its surface in detail from 1990 to 1994. Other missions, such as ESA\'s Venus Express, have studied the planet\'s atmosphere and climate.\n
            \nSome interesting facts about Venus include:\n
            \n1.Venus is often referred to as Earth\'s \"sister planet\" due to its similar size, mass, and composition. However, the two planets have very different environments and surface conditions.\n
            \n2.Venus rotates in the opposite direction to most other planets in the solar system, with the sun rising in the west and setting in the east.\n
            \n3.Venus has phases, like the moon, as seen from Earth.\n
            \n4.Venus is named after the Roman goddess of love and beauty.\n
            \n5.Because of its proximity and similarity to Earth, Venus has been a popular subject of science fiction and popular culture.\n

        </item>

        <item>
            Earth is the third planet from the sun and is the only planet in our solar system known to support life. It has a diameter of approximately 12,742 kilometers and a mass of about 5.97 x 10^24 kilograms.\n
            \nEarth is composed of several layers, including a solid inner core, a liquid outer core, a mantle, and a crust. The planet\'s atmosphere is also divided into several layers, including the troposphere, stratosphere, mesosphere, thermosphere, and exosphere. The atmosphere is mainly composed of nitrogen (78%) and oxygen (21%), with small amounts of other gases such as carbon dioxide, methane, and neon.\n
            \nEarth is known for its diverse and dynamic environment, with a wide range of ecosystems, climates, and geological features. The planet\'s surface is approximately 70% water, with the remaining 30% consisting of landmasses, including continents and islands. Earth\'s climate is driven by the interaction between the atmosphere, oceans, and land, with factors such as solar radiation, atmospheric gases, and ocean currents influencing global temperature and weather patterns.\n
            \nEarth is home to a wide variety of life, from single-celled organisms to complex multicellular organisms. The planet\'s biosphere is interconnected, with organisms interacting with each other and their environment in complex ways. Humans are one of the most dominant species on the planet and have had a significant impact on the environment and other species.\n
            \nSome interesting facts about Earth include:\n
            \n1.Earth is the only known planet with liquid water on its surface, which is essential for the survival of most known life forms.\n
            \n2.Earth\'s magnetic field, which is generated by the planet\'s core, protects the planet from harmful solar radiation and helps to maintain the atmosphere.\n
            \n3.Earth has a relatively large moon, which has played an important role in stabilizing the planet\'s rotation and tides.\n
            \n4.Earth experiences four seasons, which are caused by the tilt of the planet\'s axis relative to its orbit around the sun.\n
            \n5.Earth\'s rotation is gradually slowing down due to tidal forces, which will eventually cause the planet to have longer days.\n
            \n6.Earth is estimated to be around 4.5 billion years old and has undergone significant changes over its history, including the formation of continents, the evolution of life, and the impact of asteroid and comet impacts.\n
        </item>

        <item>
            Mars is the fourth planet from the sun and is also known as the "Red Planet" due to its reddish appearance in the night sky. It has a diameter of approximately 6,779 kilometers and a mass of about 11% that of Earth.\n
            \nMars has a thin atmosphere composed mainly of carbon dioxide, with small amounts of nitrogen and argon. The atmosphere is not thick enough to support life as we know it, and its surface is exposed to harsh radiation from the sun due to the lack of a protective magnetic field.\n
            \nMars is known for its surface features, which include vast deserts, canyons, volcanoes, and impact craters. The planet has the largest volcano in the solar system, called Olympus Mons, which is over three times taller than Mount Everest on Earth. Mars also has the longest canyon in the solar system, called Valles Marineris, which is over 4,000 kilometers long and up to 7 kilometers deep.\n
            \nMars has two small moons, Phobos and Deimos, which are thought to be captured asteroids. The moons are irregularly shaped and have heavily cratered surfaces.\n
            \nMars has been the subject of several missions by space agencies around the world, including NASA\'s Mars rovers and orbiters, which have studied the planet\'s geology, climate, and potential for life. The planet is also a popular target for future human exploration and colonization.\n
            \nSome interesting facts about Mars include:\n
            \n1.Mars has a day and night cycle similar to Earth, with a day lasting approximately 24.6 hours.\n
            \n2.Mars experiences seasons, which are caused by the planet\'s tilt and its elliptical orbit around the sun.\n
            \n3.Mars has polar ice caps, which are composed of frozen carbon dioxide and water.\n
            \n4.Mars is home to the largest canyon in the solar system, called Valles Marineris.\n
            \n5.Mars is named after the Roman god of war due to its reddish appearance, which was associated with blood by the ancient Romans.\n
            \n6.Mars has the potential for future terraforming, which would involve changing the planet\'s environment to make it more habitable for humans.\n
        </item>

        <item>
            Jupiter is the fifth planet from the sun and is the largest planet in our solar system. It has a diameter of approximately 142,984 kilometers, which is more than 11 times the diameter of Earth, and a mass of about 318 times that of Earth.\n
            \nJupiter is composed mainly of hydrogen and helium gas, and does not have a solid surface like the terrestrial planets. Instead, its outer layers are composed of a dense mixture of gas and liquid, which gradually transitions into a metallic hydrogen layer deep in the planet\'s interior.\n
            \nJupiter has a thick atmosphere composed of colorful bands of clouds that rotate around the planet\'s axis. These bands are caused by the planet\'s fast rotation, which completes one rotation in less than 10 hours. Jupiter\'s atmosphere is also home to the Great Red Spot, a giant storm that has been raging for centuries and is larger than the size of Earth.\n
            \nJupiter has a strong magnetic field, which is the strongest of all the planets in our solar system. The magnetic field traps charged particles from the sun, creating intense radiation belts around the planet.\n
            \nJupiter has at least 79 known moons, the four largest of which are called the Galilean moons: Io, Europa, Ganymede, and Callisto. These moons are some of the largest in our solar system and are thought to have subsurface oceans that could potentially harbor life.\n
            \nJupiter is a popular target for exploration by space agencies around the world. Several missions have been sent to Jupiter, including the Galileo spacecraft, which orbited the planet from 1995 to 2003, and the Juno spacecraft, which has been in orbit around Jupiter since 2016 and is studying the planet\'s magnetic field, atmosphere, and interior structure.\n
            \nSome interesting facts about Jupiter include:\n
            \n1.Jupiter has the shortest day of any planet in our solar system, with one rotation taking less than 10 hours.\n
            \n2.Jupiter\'s magnetic field is so strong that it can affect the behavior of other planets in our solar system.\n
            \n3.Jupiter\'s Great Red Spot is a giant storm that has been raging for at least 350 years and is larger than the size of Earth.\n
            \n4.Jupiter has a ring system, although it is much less visible than Saturn\'s rings.\n
            \n5.Jupiter is the largest planet in our solar system and has more than twice the mass of all the other planets in our solar system combined.\n
        </item>

        <item>
            Saturn is the sixth planet from the sun and is the second largest planet in our solar system after Jupiter. It has a diameter of approximately 116,460 kilometers and a mass of about 95 times that of Earth.\n
            \nSaturn is composed mainly of hydrogen and helium gas, with a small rocky core at its center. It has a thick atmosphere composed of colorful bands of clouds that rotate around the planet\'s axis. These bands are similar to those seen on Jupiter, but are less pronounced.\n
            \nSaturn is well-known for its impressive ring system, which consists of thousands of individual rings composed mainly of ice particles and dust. The rings extend outward from the planet\'s equator for a distance of up to 175,000 kilometers.\n
            \nSaturn has at least 82 known moons, the largest of which is called Titan. Titan is the only moon in our solar system known to have a thick atmosphere, and it has a complex chemistry that includes hydrocarbons and nitrogen.\n
            \nSaturn also has several other interesting moons, including Enceladus, which has geysers that spew water vapor and ice particles into space, and Mimas, which has a large impact crater that makes it resemble the "Death Star" from the Star Wars movies.\n
            \nSaturn has a weak magnetic field, which is about 1/20th the strength of Jupiter\'s magnetic field. However, Saturn\'s magnetosphere is still strong enough to trap charged particles from the sun and create auroras at the planet\'s poles.\n
            \nSaturn has been the subject of several missions by space agencies around the world, including NASA\'s Cassini spacecraft, which orbited the planet from 2004 to 2017 and made numerous discoveries about the planet and its moons.\n
            \nSome interesting facts about Saturn include:\n
            \n1.Saturn\'s ring system is the most extensive and complex ring system of any planet in our solar system.\n
            \n2.Saturn has the second largest moon in our solar system, called Titan, which has a thick atmosphere and a complex chemistry.\n
            \n3.Saturn\'s weak magnetic field is still strong enough to create auroras at the planet\'s poles.\n
            \n4.Saturn\'s largest moon, Titan, is larger than the planet Mercury.\n
            \n5.Saturn is named after the Roman god of agriculture and wealth.\n
        </item>

        <item>
            Uranus is the seventh planet from the sun and is the third largest planet in our solar system. It has a diameter of approximately 50,724 kilometers and a mass of about 14.5 times that of Earth.\n
            \nUranus is composed mainly of hydrogen, helium, and methane gas, with a small rocky core at its center. It has a thick atmosphere composed of hydrogen and helium, along with trace amounts of methane that give the planet its blue-green color.\
            \nUranus is unique among the planets in our solar system in that it rotates on its side, with its axis tilted at an angle of about 98 degrees relative to its orbit. This means that Uranus experiences extreme seasons, with one pole facing the sun for 42 years while the other pole faces away from the sun for the same period.\n
            \nUranus has a weak magnetic field, which is tilted at an angle of about 60 degrees relative to the planet\'s axis of rotation. This unusual orientation causes the magnetic field to wobble as the planet rotates, which can create auroras at the planet\'s poles.\n
            \nUranus has at least 27 known moons, the largest of which is called Titania. It also has a system of 13 faint rings that are composed mainly of ice particles and dust.\n
            \nUranus has been visited by only one spacecraft, NASA\'s Voyager 2 probe, which flew by the planet in 1986 and made numerous discoveries about the planet and its moons.\n
            \nSome interesting facts about Uranus include:\n
            \n1.Uranus is the only planet in our solar system that rotates on its side.\n
            \n2.Uranus has an extreme axial tilt of about 98 degrees, which causes it to experience extreme seasons.\n
            \n3.Uranus has a faint ring system, which was discovered by astronomers in 1977.\n
            \n4.Uranus has a weak magnetic field that is tilted at an angle of about 60 degrees relative to the planet\'s axis of rotation.\n
            \n5.Uranus is named after the Greek god of the sky.\n
        </item>

        <item>
            Neptune is the eighth and farthest known planet from the sun in our solar system. It has a diameter of approximately 49,244 kilometers and a mass of about 17 times that of Earth.\n
            \nNeptune is composed mainly of hydrogen, helium, and methane gas, with a small rocky core at its center. It has a thick atmosphere composed mainly of hydrogen and helium, along with trace amounts of methane that give the planet its blue color.\n
            \nNeptune has a very dynamic atmosphere, with high-speed winds that can reach up to 2,100 kilometers per hour, making them the fastest in the solar system. The planet also has a series of dark spots and bright clouds, similar to Jupiter\'s Great Red Spot.\n
            \nNeptune has 14 known moons, the largest of which is called Triton. Triton is an icy moon that is thought to have been captured by Neptune\'s gravity and has a highly unusual orbit that is tilted relative to the planet\'s equator.\n
            \nNeptune also has a system of faint rings that are composed mainly of dust particles. The rings were discovered by the Voyager 2 spacecraft, which flew by the planet in 1989.\n
            \nNeptune has a strong magnetic field, which is tilted at an angle of about 47 degrees relative to the planet\'s axis of rotation. This magnetic field traps charged particles from the solar wind and creates auroras at the planet\'s poles.\n
            \nNeptune has been visited by only one spacecraft, NASA\'s Voyager 2 probe, which flew by the planet in 1989 and made numerous discoveries about the planet and its moons.\n
            \nSome interesting facts about Neptune include:\n
            \n1.Neptune is the farthest planet from the sun in our solar system.\n
            \n2.Neptune has a very dynamic atmosphere, with high-speed winds that are the fastest in the solar system.\n
            \n3.Neptune has a system of dark spots and bright clouds, similar to Jupiter\'s Great Red Spot.\n
            \n4.Neptune has a strong magnetic field that is tilted relative to the planet\'s axis of rotation.\n
            \n5.Neptune is named after the Roman god of the sea.\n
        </item>
    </string-array>

</resources>